This video introduces the learning algorithm for a linear neuron.
这个视频将介绍线性神经元学习算法。
This is quite like the learning algorithm for a perceptron, but it achieves
其形式和感知器算法很类似， 但是达成的结果不一样。
something different. In a perceptron, what's happening is the
感知器中，参数发生变化，
weight, so always getting closer to a good set of weights.
参数不停向好的参数集合逼近。
In a linear neuron, the outputs are always getting closer to the target outputs.
在线性神经元算法中， 输出不停的向目标输出逼近。
The perception convergence procedure works by ensuring that when we change the
感知器算法收敛， 是因为我们确保了每次我们改变参数权重，
weights, we get closer to a good set of weights.
我们都向好的参数集合逼近。
That type of guarantee cannot be extended to more complex networks.
这个保证不能扩展到复杂的网络。
Because in more complex networks when you average two good set of weights, you might
在复杂的网络中， 当你对两个好的参数的集合取平均时，
get a bad set of weights. So for multilayer neural networks, we
你有可能得到一个坏的参数集合。 所以在多层神经网络中，
don't use the perceptron learning procedure.
我们不使用感知器学习算法。
And to prove that when they're learning something is improving, we don't use the
要证明复杂神经网络在提高其学习效果， 我们不能使用同样的证明方法。
same kind of proof at all. They should never have been called
他们不能被称为多层感知器。
multilayer perceptrons. It's partly my fault and I'm sorry.
这部分也有我的错在里面，抱歉了。
For multilayer nets we're gonna need a different way to show that the learning
对于多层神经网络， 我们需要使用其他方法来证明算法的确在工作。
procedure makes progress. Instead of showing that the weights get
这里我们不再证明参数正在逼近正确的参数，
closer to a good set of weights, we're gonna show that the actual output values
相反，我们会证明实际的输出正在逼近真实的输出。
get closer to the target output values. This can be true even for non-convex
这种证明方式，对于
problems in which averaging the weights of two good solutions does not give you a
非凸问题也有效， 非凸问题中，两个好的解的平均值并不能给出一个好的解。
good solution. It's not true for perceptual learning.
感知器不是这样。
In perceptual learning, the outputs as a whole can get further away from the target
在感知器学习中， 当参数向好的参数逼近时，
outputs even though the weights are getting closer to good sets of weights.
输出作为一个整体有可能更加偏离实际的输出。
The simplest example of learning in which you're making the outputs get closer to
让输出逼近实际输出的最简单的例子
the target outputs is learning in a linear neuron with a squared error measure.
就是平方误差度量下线性神经元学习。
Linear neurons, which are also called linear filters in electrical engineering,
线性神经元，在电气工程中被称为线性滤波，
have a real valued output that's simply the weighted sum of their outputs.
简单的讲输入带权重加和以后输出。
So the output Y, which is the neuron's estimate of the target value, is the sum
神经元对于目标输出的估计，输出Y，
over all the inputs i of a weight vector times an input vector.
等于所有输入i上，输入向量乘以权重向量后的加和。
So we can write it in summation form or we can write it in vector notation.
我们可以将其用加法公式或者使用矢量公式形式化下来。
The aim of the learning is to minimize the error summed over all training cases.
学习的目标是使所有的训练样本上错误的加和最小。
We need a measure of that error and to keep life simple, we use the square
我们需要一个错误的度量，为了简单起见，
difference between the target output and the actual output.
我们使用真实输出和实际输出误差的平方。
So one question is why don't we just solve it analytically.
有个问题是我们干嘛不直接求解，
It's straightforward to write down a set of equations with one equation per
对于每一个训练样本，我们都可以写下一个等式，
training case, and to solve for the best set of weights.
然后很直接的对其进行求解，得到最优的权重。
That's the standard engineering approach, and so why don't we use it?
这是标准的工程方法，为什么不这么做捏？
The first answer, and the scientific answer, is we'd like to understand what
第一个答案，或者说从科研而言， 我们试图理解真正的神经元如何工作，
real neurons might be doing, and they're probably not solving a set of equations
其应该不是去推导求解了一堆等式。
symbolically. An engineering answer is that we want a
从工程角度，
method that we can then generalize to multilayer, nonlinear networks.
我们希望得到一种能泛化到多层，非线性网络的方法。
The analytic solution relies on it being linear and having a squared error measure.
解析解局限于线性神经元和平方误差度量。
An iterative method, which we're gonna see next, is usually less efficient, but much
下面要谈的迭代法，效率较低，
easier to generalize to more complex systems.
但是容易泛化到复杂的系统。
So I'm now gonna go through a toy example that illustrates an iterative method for
下面我要讲解一个简单的例子， 说明迭代法是如何求解线性神经元的权重参数的。
finding the weights of a linear neuron. Suppose that every day, you get lunch at a
假设每天中午你都在一个咖啡厅吃午餐。
cafeteria. And your diet consists entirely of fish,
你的食谱是鱼，薯条和番茄酱。
chips, and ketchup. Each day, you order several portions of
每天你都点不同份的鱼，薯条和番茄酱，
each, but on different days, it's different numbers of portions.
每天都不同份。
The cashier only shows you the total price of the meal, but after a few days, you
收银员仅仅告诉你这一餐的总价， 一些日子以后，
ought to be able to figure out what the price is for each portion of each kind of
你应该能够说出每一种食物的单价。
thing. In the iterative approach, you start with
迭代法中，你一开始随机的猜测食品的价格，
random guesses for the prices of portions. And then you adjust these guesses so that
然后你对猜测进行调整
you get a better fit to the prices that the cashier tells you.
使得其更加符合收银员给出的价格，
Those are the observed prices of whole meals.
即这一餐的总价。
So each meal, you get a price and that gives you a linear constraint on the
所以每一餐，你都得到一个总价， 其给出了单个食品价格的一个线性约束。
prices of the individual portions. It looks like this, the price of the whole
这一餐的总价，等于
meal is the number of portion of fish, x fish, times the cost of a portion of fish,
鱼的份数，x fish，乘以每份鱼的价格，w sifh，
w fish. And the same for chips and ketchup.
对于薯条和番茄酱，同样如此。
So the prices of the portions are like the weights of a linear neuron.
食品的价格在这里类似于线性神经元的权重。
And we can think of the whole weight vector as being the price of a portion of
我们可以把整个权重向量看作为一份鱼，
fish, the price of a portion of chips, and the price of a portion of ketchup.
一份薯条，一份番茄酱的价格。
We're going to start with guesses for these prices and then we're going to
我们开始猜测这些价格，
adjust the guesses slightly, so that we agree better with what the cashier says.
对其微调，使得其符合收银员给出的数字。
So let's suppose that the true weights that the cashier using to figure out the
假设收银员收钱时使用的真实权重为
price, are 150 for a portion of fish, 50 for portion of chips and a 100 for a
150一份鱼，50一份薯条，100一份番茄酱。
portion of Ketchup. For the meals shown here, that will lead
图示的一餐，花费了850。
to a price of 850. So that's going to be our target value.
这是我们的目标值，
That suppose that we start with guesses, but each portion costs 50.
假设我们开始猜测，每种食物的价格都是50。
So for the meal with two portions of fish, five of chips, and three of ketchup, we're
对于两份鱼，5份薯条，3份番茄酱的一餐，
going to initially think that the price should be 500.
我们初始认为其价格是500。
That gives us a residual error of 350. The residual error is the difference
这个使得我们有了350的残差，
between what the cashier says and what we think the price should be with our current
残差试着我们使用目前的权重猜测的价格和 收银员给出来的价格的差异。
weights. We're then gonna use the delta rule for
然后我们使用德尔塔定律来修正食品的价格。
revising our prices of portions. We make the change in a weight, delta WI
我们对权重进行变化，delta Wi
be equal to a learning rate, epsilon times the number of portions of the i-th thing,
等于学习率epsilon乘以第i个食品的份数，乘以残差，
times the residual error. The difference between the target and our
即目标输出和我们估计值的差值。
estimate. So if we make the learning rate be one
这里我们将学习率设为1/35，
over 35, so the maths stays simple, then the learning rate times the residual error
在这里学习率乘以残差等于10，计算会简单，
for this particular example is ten. And so, our change in the weight for fish
所以，鱼价格权重的变化应该为2乘以10，
will be two times ten. We'll increase that weight by twenty.
我们要把鱼的价格加20.
Our change in the weight for chips will be five times ten.
薯条价格权重的变化是5乘以10。
And our change in the weight for ketchup will be three times ten.
番茄酱价格权重的变化为3乘以10。
That'll give us new weights of 70, 100, and 80.
这里我们得到70,100和80。
And notice, the weight for chips actually got worse.
请注意，薯条的价格权重变得错误了。
There's no guarantee with this kind of learning that the individual weights will
这种学习算法不能保证每个单独的权重始终会变好。
keep getting better. What's getting better is the difference
变好的是收银员给出的价格
between what the cashier says and our estimate.
和我们估计的价格的差异。
So now, we're going to derive the delta rule.
现在我们来推导德尔塔定律，
We start by defining the arrow measure, which is simply our squared residual
我们从定义箭头所指的误差度量开始， 即训练集上的残差平方和。
summed over all training cases. That is the squared difference between the
其是目标值和神经网络或者线性神经元预测值差的平方。
Squared, in some liberal training cases. And we put a one-half in front, which will
我们在前面放置了一个1/2，其可以消去求导时的2。
cancel the two, when we differentiate. We now differentiate that error measure
然后我们开始用某个权重，Wi，对误导度量进行求导。
with respect to one of the weights, WI. To do that differentiation we need to use
求导时我们需要使用链式法则。
the chain rule. The chain rule says that how the error
链式法则说明了我们改变权重时错误度量是如何改变的，
changes as we change a weight, will be how the output changes as we change the
其等于我们变化改变权重时输出的变化，
weight, times how the error changes as we change the output.
乘以我们改变输出是错误度量的变化。
The chain rule is easy to remember, you just cancel those two DYs but you can only
链式法则很容易记忆， 你可以消去这两个DY，
do that when there's no mathematicians looking.
不过有数学家在场可不要这么做哦。
The reason the first one, DY by DW is written with a curly D is because it's a
第一个DY对DW，用了花体的D，这是因为其是偏导。
partial derivative. That is, there's many different weights
就是说，你可以改变很多的权重来改变输出，
you can change to change the output. And here, we're just considering the
在这里，你仅仅改变权重 i。
change to weight i. So, DY by DWi, is actually equal to Xi,
所以 DY 对DWi 求导，等于Xi。
and that's because Y is just Wi times Xi, and DE by DY, is just T minus Y, because
因为 Y等于 Wi乘以Xi。DE对DY求导，等于T减去Y，
when we differentiate that T minus Y squared, and use the half to cancel the
这是因为我们对T减去Y的平方求导，然后用1/2消去了2， 最后得到了T减去Y。
two we just get T minus Y. So our learning rule is now, we change the
所以我们得到了学习的规则，
weights by an amount that's equal to the learning rate epsilon times the derivative
我们使用学习率 epsilon乘以错误度量E对权重wi的导数，
of the error with respect to a weight, to E by DWi.
来对权重进行调整。
And with a minus sign in front cuz we want the error to go down.
最前方加了负号，是因为我们想让错误变小。
And that minus sign cancels the minus sign in the line above and we get that.
这个负号可以和我们上面公式中得到的负号对消。
The change in a weight is the sum of all training cases of the learning rate times
权重的变化等于所有训练样本上
the input value times the difference between the target and actual outputs.
学习率乘以输入值，乘以目标值和实际输出值之差的总和。
Now we can ask how does this learning procedure, this delta rule, behave?
我们现在可以问，这个学习过程，德尔塔定律，是如何运行的咧？
Does this, for example, eventually get the right answer?
其最终能给出正确结果么？
There may be no perfect answer. It may be that we give the linear neuron a
也许没有完美的答案。 我们可以给线性神经元一系列的训练样本
bunch of training cases with desired answers.
以及期望的输出，
And there's no set of weights that'll give the desired answer.
但是并不存在能够产生期望输出的权重。
There's still some set of weights that gets the best approximation on all those
但是仍然存在一些权重，能够最好的近似训练样本，
training cases, minimizes that error measure.
最小化错误度量。
Some that are all training cases. And if we make the learning rate small
如果学习率最够的小，
enough and we learn for long enough, we can get as close as we like to that best
学习时间最够长，我们是能逼近最好的解的。
answer. Another question is, how quickly do we get
另一个问题是我们多块能得到最优解。
towards the best answer. And even for a linear system.
即便是一个线性系统，
The learning can be quite slow in this kind of intricate learning.
在这种复杂的学习过程中，学习也可能很慢。
If two input dimensions are highly correlated, its very hard to tell how much
如果两个输入维度高度相关，就很难
of the sum of the weight on both input dimensions should be attributed to each
把两者之和分别对应到每个输入维度上去。
input dimension. So if for example, you always get the same
比如说，你总是点同样分数的番茄酱和薯条，
number of portions of ketchup and chips is, we can't decide how much of the price
你就无法说明总价中那部分来自番茄酱，
is due to the ketchup and how much is used to the chips.
那部分来自薯条。
And if they're almost always the same, it can take a long time for the learning to
如果它们总是保持这个比例 要想学到正确的
correctly attribute the price to the ketchup and the chips.
来正确区分番茄酱和薯条的价格。
There's an interesting relationship between the delta rule and the learning
在德尔塔定律和感知器学习定律之间，存在有趣的联系。
rule for perceptrons. So, if you, you use the online version of
如果你使用德尔塔定律的在线版本，
the delta rule, but we change the weights after each training case, it's quite
在每个训练样本上修改权重，
similar to the perceptron learning rule. In perceptron learning, we increment or
就和感知器学习很相似了。
decrement the weight vector by the input vector, but we only change the input
感知器学习中，预测错误时，
vector when we make an error. In the online version of the delta rule,
我们使用输入向量来增加或者减小权重向量。 德尔塔定律的在线版中，
we increment or decrement the weight vector by the imperfector.
我们也根据输入向量来增加或者减小权重向量，
But we scale that by both the residual error and the learning rate.
不过还要乘以学习率和残差。
And one annoying thing about this is we have to choose a learning rate.
这里令人恼怒的是我们要选择一个合适的学习率。
If we choose a learning rate that's too big, the system will be unstable.
如果选得太大，系统会不稳定。
And if we choose a learning rate that's too small, it will take an unnecessarily
如果选择的太小，则会花费很长时间才能
long time to, to learn a sensible set of weights
得到有意义的权重。